Preliminary Guide to the National Women's Studies Association Journal records RL.00960
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
National Women's Studies Association Journal records
1990-2008
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
National Women's Studies Association
McFadden, Margaret
RL.00960
49.5 Linear Feet
NWSA Journal, an official publication of the National Women's Studies Association, publishes interdisciplinary, multi-cultural feminist scholarship linking feminist theory with teaching and activism. Accession 2003-0263 (26,100 items; 43.5 lin. ft.; dated 1990-1998 and undated) comprises administrative files, records of the site search and other editorial board policy matters, correspondence, annual and semi-annual reports, copyedited manuscripts, readers' reports, and published manuscripts; and revisions of issues from each volume. Addition (06-006) (7 items, .1 lin. ft.; dated 1990-1998) comprises 7 issues of the NWSAction newsletter, Fall 1990-Summer 1998.Addition (06-039) (375 items, .2 lin. ft.; dated 2000-2003) contains final page proofs, abstracts, advertising, research and proposals, and correspondence generated for the special issue Gender and Modernity, Fall 2003, volume 15, number 3. Acquired as part of the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture.
49.5 Linear Ft.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The National Women's Studies Association Journal records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2003, 2006, 2007, 2009 and 2015.
Biographical Note
The NWSA Journal, an official publication of the National Women's Studies Association, publishes interdisciplinary, multi-cultural feminist scholarship linking feminist theory with teaching and activism.
Collection Overview
Accession (2003-0263) (26,100 items; lin. ft.; dated 1990-1998 and undated) comprises administrative files, records of the site search and other editorial board policy matters, correspondence, annual and semi-annual reports, copyedited manuscripts, readers' reports, and published manuscripts; and revisions of issues from each volume.
The 2006 addition (2006-0006) (7 items, 0.1 lin. ft.; dated 1990-1998) comprises 7 issues of the NWSAction newsletter, Fall 1990-Summer 1998.
The 2006 addition (2006-0039) (375 items, 0.2 lin. ft.; dated 2000-2003) contains final page proofs, abstracts, advertising, research and proposals, and correspondence generated for the special issue Gender and Modernity, Fall 2003, volume 15, number 3.
The 2007 addition (2007-0118) (2630 items; 4.8 lin. ft.; dated 2003-2007) contains manuscripts, journal submissions, proofs, and editorial files related to 2005-2007 issues. Also included are a procedure manual, correspondence, administrative and editorial files, copies of published journals (2004-2007), and newsletters. Acquired as part of the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture.
The 2009 addition (2009-0007) (29 items; 0.6 lin. ft.; dated 2003-2008) contains 4 published journals (2007-2008) and electronic materials used in the creation of the journal, including 19 CDs, 5 zip discs, and 1 USB key. Acquired as part of the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture.
The 2015 addition (2009-0098) (0.3 lin. ft.; dated 1978-2011) contains 1 box of material documenting the work of the National Women's Studies Association Journal from Margaret (Maggie) McFadden. It comprises administrative files, records of the site search and other editorial board policy matters, correspondence, journal proposals and information about applicants considered for employment. Acquired as part of the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture.
Women's studies -- Periodicals; National Women's Studies Association; Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture; McFadden, Margaret
- Accession, 2003 (2003-0263), 29 boxes
  Scope and Contents note
  Accession (26100 items; 43.5 lin. ft.; dated 1990-1998 and n.d.) comprises administrative files, records of the site search and other editorial board policy matters, correspondence, annual and semi-annual reports, copyedited manuscripts, readers' reports, and published manuscripts; and revisions of issues from each volume.
  - Issues 10.1 and 10.2 (Box 1)
  - Issues 10.2 and 10.3 (Box 2)
  - Issues 10.3 and 11.1 (Box 3)
  - Issues 11.1 and 11.2 (Box 4)
  - Issues 11.2 and 11.3 (Box 5)
  - Issue 11.3 (Box 6)
  - Issue 12.1 (Box 7)
  - Issue 12.2 (Box 8)
  - Issue 12.3 (Box 9)
  - Issue 13.1 (Box 10)
  - Office files: A-E (Box 11)
  - Office files: E-F (Box 12)
  - Office files: F-N (Box 13)
  - Book review files (Box 14)
  - Revise and resubmit files (Box 15)
  - Revise and resubmit files, 1997-2000 (Box 16)
  - Revise and resubmit files, 1997-2000 (Box 17)
  - Rejected art and consent to publish (Box 17)
  - Issue 15.3 (Box 18)
  - Miscellaneous business files (Box 18)
  - Indexing information (Box 19)
  - Promotional sheets (Box 19)
  - Office files: O-Z (Box 19)
  - Issue 14.1 (Box 20)
  - Issue 14.3 (end) (Box 21)
  - Issue 15.1 (first part) (Box 21)
  - Issue 13.2 (Box 22)
  - Issue 15.2 (Box 23)
  - Issue 14.2 (first part) (Box 24)
  - Issue 15.3 (box 1) (Box 25)
  - Issue 15.1 (end) (Box 26)
  - Issue 14.2 (end) (Box 27)
  - Issue 14.3 (first part) (Box 27)
  - Issue 13.3 (Box 28)
  - Issue 15.2 (end) (Box 29)
  - Issue 15.3 (Box 29)
- Accession, 2006 (2006-0006), 1 boxes
  Addition (7 items, .1 lin. ft.; dated 1990-1998) comprises 7 issues of the NWSAction newsletter, Fall 1990-Summer 1998.
  - NWSAction newsletter, 1990-1998 (Box 1)
- Accession, 2006 (2006-0039), 1 boxes
  Addition (375 items, .2 lin. ft.; dated 2000-2003) contains final page proofs, abstracts, advertising, research and proposals, and correspondence generated for the special issue Gender and Modernity, Fall 2003, volume 15, number 3.
  - Proofs, abstracts, advertising, research and proposals, and correspondence (Box 1)
- Accession, 2007 (2007-0118), 8 boxes
  The 2007 addition (2007-0118)(2630 items; 4.8 lin. ft.; dated 2003-2007) contains manuscripts, journal submissions, proofs, and editorial files related to 2005-2007 issues. Also included are a procedure manual, correspondence, administrative and editorial files, copies of published journals (2004-2007), and newsletters.
  - Issue 18.3 (Box 1)
    Separated Material
    Four 3.5" diskettes have been removed from the folder labeled 18.3. The contents of these disks have been migrated to an archival server.
  - Issue 18.3 (Box 2)
  - Abstracts for back issues (Box 2)
  - NWSA Journal Procedure Manual, 2 folders (Box 2)
    One CD-R has been removed from this folder and its contents have been migrated to an archival server.
  - Issue 19.1 (Box 3)
    One CD-R has been removed from the folder labeled 19.1 Flamenbaum. One CD-R has been removed from the folder labeled Hankin imgages/permissions 19.1. The contents of these disks have been migrated to an archival server.
  - Issue 19.2 (Box 4)
  - Issue 19.2 (Box 5)
  - Issue 17.2 (Box 5)
  - Issue 17.2 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence, 2003-2007 (Box 7)
  - Submissions and revisions (Box 7)
  - Special issue proposals (Box 7)
  - Published journals 16.1-19.1, 2004-2007 (Box 8)
  - Digital media (Box 8, Server NWSAJ 2007-0118)
- Accession (2009-0007), 2003-2008, 1 boxes
  Addition (2009-0007) (29 items; 0.1 lin. ft.; dated 2003-2008) contains 4 published journals (2007-2008) and electronic materials used in the creation of the journal, including 19 CDs, 5 zip discs, and 1 USB key. Acquired as part of the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture.
  - NWSA Journals 19.2, 19.3, 20.1, and 20.2 (Box 1)
    19 CDs, 5 zip discs, and 1 USB key have been removed from the collection and migrated to an archival server for electronic preservation.
- Accession (2015-0098), 1978-2011
  - National Women's Studies Association, 1978 (Box 41)
  - National Women's Studies Association, 1979 (Box 41)
  - Denver NWSA, November 10-14, 2010 (Box 41)
  - Denver NWSA, November 10-14, 2010 (Box 41)
  - NWSAJ Board Meeting, November 10-14, 1996 (Box 41)
  - Women's Worlds Ottawa, 2011 (Box 41)
  - NWSAJ Site Visit, August 15-16, 1996 (Box 41)
  - NWSAJ Applications (Box 41)
  - NWSAJ- Journal Proposals (1 of 2) (Box 41)
  - NWSAJ- Journal Proposals (2 of 2) (Box 41)
  - Notes & Correspondence (1 of 3) (Box 41)
  - Notes & Correspondence (2 of 3) (Box 41)
  - Notes & Correspondence (3 of 3) (Box 41)